Ganeev Singh

(562) 646-6367 | GANEEVS@UCLA.EDU | SAN FRANCISCO, CA 94105 HTTPS://WWW.LINKEDIN.COM/IN/GANEEVSINGH

PERSONAL PROFILE

For most of my life, I have been fascinated by the field of medicine and my last two years of college allowed me to explore the business sector as well. After graduating with honors from UCLA, I moved up to San Francisco to work as an Associate Consultant at a healthcare consulting firm. Next year, I will be applying to a joint MD/MBA program with a matriculation date of Fall 2019. My overall career goal is to become a physician who runs healthcare and technology entrepreneurship ventures on the side that benefit people of limited means who have nowhere to turn to for help. I am also interested in higher level hospital management, running multiple hospitals one day and impacting lives in my community and beyond.

EDUCATION

B.S. in Psychobiology, minor in Entrepreneurship

September 2013 – June 2017

University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA), Los Angeles, CA

College Honors & Magna Cum Laude Latin Honors (Cumulative GPA: 3.82)

Certificate in Patient Experience and Pre-Licensed Clinical Care

February 2017 - May 2017

University of California, Los Angeles - Fielding School of Public Health, Los Angeles, CA

PUBLICATIONS

Dagnew, R., Lin, E., Agatep, J., Cheng, M., Jann, A., Quach, V., Monroe, M., **Singh, G.**, Minasyan, A., Hakimian, J., Kee, T., Cushman, J., & Walwyn, W. (2017). *CerebraLux: A low cost, open source, wireless probe for optogenetic stimulation*. Submitted for publication - under review.

Shadfar, A., Crane, O., Hakimian, J., **Singh, G.**, Heinzerling, K., & Walwyn, W. (2017). *Is pain protective of prescription opioid misuse?* Unpublished manuscript.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

HEALTH SCHOLAR | COPE HEALTH SOLUTIONS AT ADVENTIST HEALTH GLENDALE, GLENDALE, CA

February 2017 - June 2017

- Assisted medical staff members in preparing and positioning patients for procedures by performing direct patient care (e.g. bathing and changing patients; logrolling patients; acquiring vital signs)
- Independently positioned telemetry leads, ambulate, and feed patients upon RN approval
- Assisted in performing post-mortem care
- Shadowed nurses, physicians, and healthcare professionals to observe medical procedures in a sterile environment
- Assisted the department's unit secretary with paperwork, answering phones, and answering patient call lights as needed
- Coordinated communication between patients, family members, medical professionals, and administrative staff

PATIENT TRANSPORT | RONALD REAGAN UCLA MEDICAL CENTER

February 2017 - June 2017

Transported patients and visitors to and from procedure rooms, patient rooms, and the hospital lobby

RESEARCH ASSISTANT | UCLA HATOS RESEARCH CENTER FOR NEUROPHARMACOLOGY

November 2014 - June 2017

- Spearheaded independent experiments to understand chronic neuropathic pain and opiate/cocaine addiction
- Operated on mice to surgically implant optic fibers in key areas of their brains for optogenetic experiments
- Performed subcutaneous and intravenous injections on mice during drug addiction experiments
- Conducted DNA cloning, sequencing, and mapping of the D1 and D2 brain pathways using qPCR and gel electrophoresis

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

INTERN | CAPRICOR THERAPEUTICS INC., BEVERLY HILLS, CA

April 2017 - June 2017

Produced market research reports on existing and potential indications to help guide clinical and business decisions

FINANCIAL REPRESENTATIVE INTERN | NORTHWESTERN MUTUAL, LOS ANGELES, CA

January 2016 - November 2016

- Consulted with clients to determine financial goals, and offered research-based advice to meet clients' needs
- Effectively developed clients' comprehensive financial plans regarding retirement planning, estate planning, investment portfolios, insurance needs, and tax strategies
- Continuously networked and built individual client base, through referred prospecting and LinkedIn outreach
- Invited to be a part of the Northwestern Mutual iLead top intern program to hone leadership skills

OPERATIONS COORDINATOR | ARBORBRIDGE, LOS ANGELES, CA

January 2016 - June 2016

- Initiated comprehensive income and expense analyses that contributed to the acquisition of another company
- Communicated financial information with department heads according to their needs
- Identified areas for improvement in business processes and delivered strategic recommendations to senior management
- Handled inquiries through quality customer care and liaised with cross-functional teams in support of customer needs

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

UNDERGRADUATE TEACHING ASSISTANT | UCLA DEPARTMENT OF CHEMISTRY & BIOCHEMISTRY

April 2017 - June 2017

• Facilitated students' learning of organic chemistry through the development of organic chemistry teaching modules on BACON (Biology and Chemistry Online Notes and Tutorials). BACON connects organic chemistry to health and pop culture

OPERATIONS COMMITTEE | UCLA BRUIN MEDICAL ENTREPRENEURS

January 2017 - June 2017

• Managed the operations of the organization (e.g. building a quarterly calendar, running weekly events, and recording meeting notes)

RESIDENT ASSISTANT | UCLA RESIDENTIAL LIFE

September 2014 – June 2017

- Developed and implement proactive educational and community building programs, such as financial awareness piggy bank making, jumpstart to a strong resume and LinkedIn profile, and interactive ice cream socials
- Served on-call regularly for emergency and crisis response in a community of over 1000 residents
- Trained to assist EMS, University Police, Campus Safety Officers, and University Fire Department
- Coordinated opportunities for team development with the professional staff

MARKETING DIRECTOR | UCLA BHAGAT PURAN SINGH HEALTH INITIATIVE

September 2014 – June 2017

- Assessed more than 100 patients and recorded BMI, blood glucose levels, blood pressure, and other health data
- Led a group of 30 student activists in health awareness campaigns and free medical aid clinics at local churches
- Prepared monthly audits, detailing the finances and activities of the organization
- Created compelling presentations for organization meetings on topics such as healthy eating habits and effective communicative techniques for spreading health education in the community

HONORS AND SCHOLARSHIPS

UCLA Phi Beta Kappa Honors Society, UCLA
UCLA College Honors, UCLA
Exemplary Service Award, COPE Health Solutions
Staff Scholar, UCLA Residential Life
UCLA True Bruin Distinguished Senior Award Finalist, UCLA
November 2016

Dean's Honors List, UCLA Spring 2014 – Spring 2017 UCLA Achievement Scholarship, UCLA UCLA Alumni Scholarship, UCLA 2013 – 2017 2013 – 2017

Team Recognition Award, *UCLA Residential Life*October 2014

SKILLS

Software: Advanced proficiency in MS Office Suite; Experience with QuickBooks and Photoshop

Foreign Languages: Advanced fluency in Hindi and Urdu

Certifications and Licenses: AHA Basic Life Support for Healthcare Professionals Certification California Life, Accident, and Health Insurance License #0K73924